Guide to the J. M. Barrie Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1686–1955; Series I; 8.13; 20 boxes
  - Letters from J. M. Barrie
    - "Clifford", 1906 January 14 (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - Clifford, W. K., Mrs., 1906–1926 (Box 5, Folder 118)
      Letter of June 8, 1926, gift of Warren H. Lowenhaupt (Yale 1914, MA 1916, PhD 1917), 1954.
    - Clodd, Edward, 1892; 1894; undated (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - Colefax, Sibyl, undated (Box 5, Folder 120)
    - Colles, William Morris, 1891–1904 (Box 5, Folder 121)
      Letter of December 2, 1891, gift of W. Robert Blum (Yale 1916), 1954.
    - Colvin, Frances Fetherstonhaugh Sitwell, 1903–1916 (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - Colvin, Ian Duncan, 1921–1927 (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - Colvin, Sidney, 1899–1922; undated (Box 5, Folder 124)
      Topics include thanking him for sending the Boxhill papers and commenting on Colvin's work on Meredith.
    - Compton, Mrs., 1919–1920 (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - Cook, Davidson, 1914 December 31 (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - Corfield, Mrs., 1919 July 23 (Box 5, Folder 127)
      Accompanied by dedication sheet inscribed by actor Frank Forbes-Robertson, September 27, 1918.
    - Cormack, O. S., 1908 July 11 (Box 5, Folder 128)
    - Cornford, L. Cope (Leslie Cope), 1899 August 5 (Box 5, Folder 129)
    - Cornford, Lawrence, 1932 May 9 (Box 5, Folder 130)
    - Cornhill Magazine (to the editor), 1885 June 19 (Box 5, Folder 131)
      Offering "The Body in the Black Box" for publication; editor at the time was James Payne.
    - Cornwallis-West, G. (George), undated (Box 5, Folder 132)
    - Courtney, W. L. (William Leonard), 1906 July 18 (Box 5, Folder 133)
      Accepting an invitation to join the Titmarsh Club, a group of Thackeray's admirers.
    - Cowell, Silbert Forrest, 1903 January 10 (Box 5, Folder 134)
    - Cowerns and Gray (?), 1908 November 3 (Box 5, Folder 135)
      Declining an offer of publication.
    - Craig, James Alexander, 1904 (Box 5, Folder 136)
      Includes a refusal to have his photograph reproduced in Great Thoughts.
    - Croxton, Arthur, 1912–1921 (Box 5, Folder 137)
      Some letters concern production details of Der Tag, Pantaloon, and The Real Thing at Last.
    - Curzon, Lady, 1915 March 31 (Box 5, Folder 138)
      Replying to her condolence note upon death of George Llewelyn Davies.
    - Dalgleish, Philip H., 1931 December 6 (Box 6, Folder 139)
    - Dallas, Miss, 1915–1916 (Box 6, Folder 140)
      Miss Dallas was an employee of H. A. Brown and Co., and the letters contain instructions from Barrie regarding changes to be made to the film The Cinema Supper at the Savoy. Mentioned are Prime Minister H. H. Asquith, The Duke of Sutherland, Mrs. Patrick Campbell, Charles Frohman, George Bernard Shaw, and G. K. Chesterton.
    - Daniell, Alfred, 1899–1935 (Box 6, Folder 141)
    - Davies, Arthur Llewelyn, 1898 May 24 (Box 6, Folder 142)
    - Davies, Margaret Llewelyn, 1917 April 16 (Box 6, Folder 143)
      Concerning Peter Llewelyn Davies' activities in France during World War I.
    - Dawson Scott, C. A. (Catharine Amy), 1934 June 6 (Box 6, Folder 144)
      Declining to attend a PEN congress in Scotland.
    - de Pass, Ronald, 1906 January 27 (Box 6, Folder 145)
    - Delafield, Mr., 1918 April 26 (Box 6, Folder 146)
      Containing references to Maude Adams and to Dear Brutus.
    - Dent, J. C., 1934 August 8 (Box 6, Folder 147)
    - Desborough, William Henry Grenfell, and Ethel, 1925–1937 (Box 6, Folder 148)
      Accompanied by one letter to Lord Desborough from "Cynthia" in Sullington, Storrington.
    - Dickens, Ethel, 1928; 1929; undated (Box 6, Folder 149)
      Concerning the typing of Barrie's manuscripts.
    - Dickinson, William Croft, 1921 October 19 (Box 6, Folder 150)
      Concerning Barrie's installation as rector of St. Andrew's University.
    - Dobson, Mrs., 1924 May 11 (Box 6, Folder 151)
    - Dodd, Francis, undated (Box 6, Folder 152)
    - Dorr, Mrs., 1896 (Box 6, Folder 153)
    - Douglas, Mr., 1902; 1903 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Drinkwater, John, 1909 April 8 (Box 6, Folder 155)
      Including note in an unidentified hand: "Will write author Sal not paid. Banker's form encl."
    - Du Maurier, Emma, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 156)
    - Duncan, Elsie, 1921 May 21 (Box 6, Folder 157)
      Accompanied by a later postcard of the Peter Pan statue in Kensington Gardens, London.
    - Duncan, Robert, 1917? Feb 16 (Box 6, Folder 158)
      Accompanied by an envelope addressed to Duncan in an unidentified hand.
    - Dunn, James Nicol, 1889–1904 (Box 6, Folder 159)
    - Eaton, Florence, 1911 October 28 (Box 6, Folder 160)
      Giving advice about a play she has written.
    - "Edith", 1919 May 13 (Box 6, Folder 161)
    - Edwards, Helen, 1899 December 19 (Box 6, Folder 162)
    - Edwards, Mr., undated (Box 6, Folder 163)
    - Elizabeth II, Queen of Great Britain, 1937 June 15 (Box 6, Folder 164)
    - Ellis, S. M. (Stewart Marsh), 1917–1931 (Box 6, Folder 165)
      Containing a description of Barrie's first meeting with George Meredith.
    - Ely (?), Mr., 1914 September 30 (Box 6, Folder 166)
    - Ervine, St. John G. (St. John Greer) and Lenora M., 1921–1933 (Box 6, Folder 167)
    - Esher, Reginald Baliol Brett, Viscount, and Eleanor, 1903–1914 (Box 6, Folder 168)
      Including a letter thanking Lord Esher for his part in securing the key to Kensington Gardens for Barrie's use.
    - Evans, Mr., 1928 October 29 (Box 6, Folder 169)
      Containing references to Francis Brett Young's My Brother Jonathan and The Black Diamond.
    - Farren, William, 1913–1926 (Box 6, Folder 170)
      Accompanied by a letter from Adelaide Farren to Cynthia Asquith (1938).
    - Ferguson, Mr., 1899 August 7 (Box 6, Folder 171)
      Declining to take a stand on some matter. Including a note in an unidentified hand: "You see he cannot get Barrie. Please tell the Central and Patrick."
    - Fielder, Mr., 1907 June 21 (Box 6, Folder 172)
    - Filippi, Miss, undated (Box 6, Folder 173)
    - Fleury, Serge, 1907 July 5 (Box 6, Folder 174)
    - Foote, Charles B., 1893 May 20 (Box 6, Folder 175)
      Removed from A Tillyloss Scandal (New York, 1893)
    - Forbes, Norman, 1926–1931 (Box 6, Folder 176)
      Containing references to Barrie's Stanway play The Wheel.
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1909 May 23 (Box 6, Folder 177)
    - Forman, H. Buxton (Harry Buxton), 1896; 1917 (Box 6, Folder 178)
      1896 letter removed from Better Dead (London, 1888) (BEIN Ip B276 B43, copy 1)
    - Forster-Bovill, W. B, undated (Box 6, Folder 179)
    - Fortescue, Mr., 1910 May 24 (Box 6, Folder 180)
    - Foss, Mr., 1910; 1917 (Box 6, Folder 181)
    - Fowell, Sir, 1923 June 30 (Box 6, Folder 182)
    - Fox, Paul Hervey, 1922 January 10 (Box 6, Folder 183)
      Containing references to H. B. Marriott Watson's works and to Barrie's association with Watson.
    - "Foy", 1925 October 27 (Box 6, Folder 184)
    - Franklin, Miss, 1902 July 4 (Box 6, Folder 185)
      Regarding a part in his play.
    - Fraser, Margaret, 1903 July 11 (Box 6, Folder 186)
    - Frensham Pond Hotel, 1901–1904; 1903 (Box 6, Folder 187)
      Confirming use of the cricket ground at Frensham.
    - Frohman, Charles, 1906–1914 (Box 6, Folder 188)
      Including letters containing references to Maude Adams and to Barrie's Peter Pan and The Dramatists Get What They Want (enclosure—copy of script for The Dramatists —wanting).
    - Furniss, Harry, 1913 June 17 (Box 6, Folder 189)
      Concerning a drawing to be made of Barrie by Furniss.
    - Furse, Charles Wellington, 1890 June 18 (Box 6, Folder 190)
    - Gawsworth, John, 1935 November 3 (Box 7, Folder 191)
      Allowing his name to be added to a committee.
    - Geddes, Mrs., 1918 February 7 (Box 7, Folder 192)
    - Geddie, John, 1922–1930 (Box 7, Folder 193)
    - Gilder, Richard Watson, 1900 June 25 (Box 7, Folder 194)
    - Gill, Mrs., 1890–1899 (Box 7, Folder 195)
    - Gilmour, Elizabeth Keltie, 1890–1937 (Box 7, Folder 196)
    - Gilmour, Thomas Lennox, 1885–1936 (Box 7, Folder 197-205)
      Collection of 252 letters from Barrie to Gilmour, and one letter from Gilmour to Barrie. Enclosures: December 13, 1902, ALS to Barrie from Walter Biggar Blaikie; April 16, 1915, cablegram to Barrie from Charles Frohman; July 11, 1915, ALS to Prime Minister Asquith from Barrie; August 3, 1912, AL (initialed) to Lewis and Lewis from T. L. Gilmour; August 3, 1912, AL (initialed) to Barclays Bank from T. L. Gilmour. Letters of May 5, 1887, and February 15, 1896, are published in Letters of J. M. Barrie, edited by Viola Meynell (New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1947).
      Letter of June 18, 1927, gift of John Wilson, 1977.
    - Gomme, Alice Bertha, undated (Box 8, Folder 206)
    - Goodman, Mr., 1913 July 22 (Box 8, Folder 207)
    - "Gordon", 1924 November 26 (Box 8, Folder 208)
    - Gordon, Ralph, 1919 December 5 (Box 8, Folder 209)
    - Gorell, Ronald Gorell Barnes, 1913–1935 (Box 8, Folder 210)
      Includes photograph of Barrie inscribed to Gorell, two autograph letters, signed, to the Times, and a typed statement, signed, regarding the Berne Convention and literary copyrights.
    - Gosse, Edmund, 1895–1928 (Box 8, Folder 211)
      The 1895 letter refers to Gosse's article about Robert Louis Stevenson, published in Century Magazine, July 1895. The 1909 letter is dated by Gosse and includes a note in his hand: "This refers to Lord Morley's refusal to let G. Meredith be buried in Westminster Abbey. E. G."
    - "Graham", 1902; 1906; undated (Box 8, Folder 212)
    - Granville-Barker, Helen, 1927–1936 (Box 8, Folder 213)
    - "Greene", 1897 July 10 (Box 8, Folder 214)
    - Grein, Jack Thomas, 1922–1925 (Box 8, Folder 215)
    - Griffith, A. P., undated (Box 8, Folder 216)
    - Grimswold, S. M., 1905 June 22 (Box 8, Folder 217)
    - Haddock, George, undated (Box 8, Folder 218)
    - Haddon, Archibald John, undated (Box 8, Folder 219)
      Removed from An Edinburgh Eleven (London, 1896) (BEIN Ip B276 E33 1896C)
    - Haggard, H. Rider (Henry Rider), 1907–1909 (Box 8, Folder 220)
    - Haig, Douglas Haig, 1926 July 15 (Box 8, Folder 221)
    - Haig, Mr., 1902 August 2 (Box 8, Folder 222)
    - Hammerton, Mrs., undated (Box 8, Folder 223)
    - Harcourt, Lewis Harcourt, 1910 April 19 (Box 8, Folder 224)
    - Hardy, Emma Lavinia Gifford, 1893 (Box 8, Folder 225)
      One letter regarding various characters in the works of Thomas Hardy and Barrie.
    - Harebin, M., 1917; 1923 (Box 8, Folder 226)
    - Harper Brothers, 1912 February 20 (Box 8, Folder 227)
      Concerning William Dean Howell's 75th birthday celebration.
    - Harrison, Frederick and daughter, 1913 January 12 (Box 8, Folder 228)
    - "Harry", 1909 May 9 (Box 8, Folder 229)
    - Harvey, Mrs., 1913 June 28 (Box 8, Folder 230)
    - Hayman, Al, 1918–1921 (Box 8, Folder 231)
      Some letters containing references to the filming of Peter Pan, Quality Street, The Little Minister, The Admirable Crichton, What Every Woman Knows, and Sentimental Tommy; the production of the plays The Truth About the Russian Dancers, A Well-remembered Voice, and Mary Rose; and to the people involved in those productions, including Maude Adams, Gerald du Maurier, David Wark Griffith, Jesse Louis Lasky, and other theater and cinema personalities.
    - Hayward, Arthur B., 1926 November 26 (Box 8, Folder 232)
    - "Headlam", 1902 April 26 (Box 8, Folder 233)
      Regarding cricket.
    - Heinemann, William, 1897; 1912 (Box 8, Folder 234)
    - Henley, William Ernest, 1895; undated (Box 8, Folder 235)
      One letter regarding the death of Barrie's mother Margaret Ogilvy Barrie.
    - "Sir Henry", 1897 January 1 (Box 8, Folder 236)
      Removed from The Admirable Crichton (1914); gift of W. Robert Blum (Yale 1916), 1954.
    - Henschel, George, 1896 (Box 8, Folder 237)
      Concerning a proposal to turn The Little Minister into a German opera.
    - Hentschel, Bertha, 1908 May 30 (Box 8, Folder 238)
    - Hentschel, Beryl, 1908 April 5 (Box 8, Folder 239)
      Concerning a map of "Never Never Land" drawn by Miss Hentschel.
    - Hentschel, Carl, 1903–1912 (Box 8, Folder 240)
    - Hepburn, Miss, 1894; undated (Box 8, Folder 241)
    - Herbert, A. P. (Alan Patrick), 1919–1935 (Box 8, Folder 242)
      Sixteen letters, mostly concerning Herbert's works.
    - Herkless, John, 1898 March 19 (Box 8, Folder 243)
      Concerning the honorary degree conferred on Barrie in 1898 by the University of St Andrews.
    - Herkomer, Hubert von, 1900 May 31 (Box 8, Folder 244)
    - Herridge, W. D., 1928 August 18 (Box 8, Folder 245)
    - Herriot, M. C., 1929; 1937 (Box 8, Folder 246)
    - Hewlett, Maurice, 1900 April 20 (Box 8, Folder 247)
    - Hicks, Seymour, 1903 March 7 (Box 8, Folder 248)
    - Hill-Brandon, Edward, 1923 January 3 (Box 8, Folder 249)
    - Hind, Mr., 1896; 1898 (Box 8, Folder 250)
    - Hodder and Stoughton, 1896; 1915 (Box 8, Folder 251)
      Enclosure (picture of Barrie) wanting.
    - "Hoh", 1907 March 2 (Box 8, Folder 252)
    - Holland, Clive, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 253)
    - Holland, (Lionel Reginald?), 1894 November 13 (Box 8, Folder 254)
    - Hollyer, Frederick, 1888 December 3 (Box 8, Folder 255)
      Concerning photographs to be made of Barrie.
    - Horder, Thomas, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 256)
      Enclosed is a letter to Horder from Windsor Castle regarding Barrie's health.
    - Horne, A. B., 1907–1913 (Box 8, Folder 257)
    - Hornung, Ernest William, 1899 June 8 (Box 8, Folder 258)
    - Hubback, Edith C. (Edith Charlotte), 1911–1923 (Box 8, Folder 259)
      Offering financial aid and literary advice to the recipient (Mrs. Francis Brown).
    - Hughes, J. D., 1903 September 21 (Box 8, Folder 260)
    - Hughes, Pryde, 1923 (Box 8, Folder 261)
      Eight letters to Hughes, who was in charge of filming The Yellow Week at Stanway. A Record of Fair Women and Brainy Men.
    - Humes, Brandon, undated (Box 8, Folder 262)
    - Hunt, Edith Holman, undated (Box 8, Folder 263)
    - Hutchinson, Thomas, 1900 May 12 (Box 8, Folder 264)
      Removed from The Wedding Guest (New York, 1900) (BEIN Ip B276 W42 1900, copy 2).
    - Huxley, Mrs., 1907 July 10 (Box 8, Folder 265)
    - Inge, Mrs., 1926 January 10 (Box 9, Folder 266)
    - Ireland, Alexander, 1889 October 6 (Box 9, Folder 267)
    - Irvine, James Colquhoun, 1927 April 26 (Box 9, Folder 268)
      Removed from Courage (London, 1922 (BEIN Ip B276.922b); gift of Henry C. Taylor (Yale 1917), 1949.
    - Irving, Henry, 1892–1898 (Box 9, Folder 269)
      Endorsed by Irving. Containing references to Barrie's The Professor's Love Story and to George Washington Cable.
    - Irving, Peter, 1875–1877 (Box 9, Folder 270)
    - Jackson, George, 1894 (Box 9, Folder 271)
      Accompanied by a letter by Barrie signed as "Tammas Haggart," and a copy of a program related to readings from Barrie's works.
    - Jackson, Holbrook, 1912 September 13 (Box 9, Folder 272)
    - Jeans, Mabel, 1924 July 9 (Box 9, Folder 273)
    - Jeune, Susan Mary Elizabeth Stewart-Mackenzie, Lady, 1893–1907 (Box 9, Folder 274)
    - Jowitt, T. Lawrence, 1914? Feb 15 (Box 9, Folder 275)
      Concerning Glasgow Repertory Theatre production.
    - Keary, C. F. (Charles Francis), 1906; 1907 (Box 9, Folder 276)
      Removed from Sentimental Tommy (London,1896) (BEIN Ip B276.896) and The Little White Bird (London, 1902) (BEIN Ip B276.902); gift of Henry C. Taylor (Yale 1917), 1949.
    - Keeble, Frederick, 1930; 1932 (Box 9, Folder 277)
    - Kemble, Henry, 1903 January 22 (Box 9, Folder 278)
    - Kennedy, Howard Angus, 1895–1932 (Box 9, Folder 279)
    - Kennedy, James H., 1899 April 16 (Box 9, Folder 280)
    - Kernahan, Coulson, 1891; 1892; undated (Box 9, Folder 281)
    - Kerr, Mr., undated (Box 9, Folder 282)
    - Kimball, Ingalls, 1896 November 1 (Box 9, Folder 283)
    - Kipling, Rudyard, 1899 May 17 (Box 9, Folder 284)
      Accompanied by printed portraits of Barrie, Kipling, and Robert Louis Stevenson.
    - Kirk, R. S., 1899 August 12 (Box 9, Folder 285)
    - Knight Company, 1921 September 23 (Box 9, Folder 286)
      Concerning John Llewelyn Davies.
    - Knight, Alfred E. (Alfred Ernest), 1902 March 6 (Box 9, Folder 287)
    - Knoblock, Edward, 1936 July 30 (Box 9, Folder 288)
    - Knowles, James, 1905 (Box 9, Folder 289)
    - Kyllman, Mr., undated (Box 9, Folder 290)
    - LaTrobe, Mr., 1920 May 14 (Box 9, Folder 291)
    - Lawrence Jellicoe, 1907 December 7 (Box 9, Folder 292)
    - Lawson, E. Webster, undated (Box 9, Folder 293)
    - "Lee", 1910 December 2 (Box 9, Folder 294)
      Concerning a dinner for John Morley.
    - Leng, John, 1904 March 4 (Box 9, Folder 295)
      Issuing an invitation to Sir John and Lady Leng to attend the 114th annual dinner of the Royal Literary Fund.
    - Lewes, Charles S., 1901 December 14 (Box 9, Folder 296)
    - Lewin, William, 1933 March 3 (Box 9, Folder 297)
    - Lewis, Mrs., 1908–1918 (Box 9, Folder 298)
    - Lindsay, Lady (Caroline Blanche Elizabeth), 1891–1894 (Box 9, Folder 299)
    - Llewelyn Davies, George, 1911–1915 (Box 9, Folder 300-303)
    - Llewelyn Davies, John and Geraldine, 1920–1937 (Box 10, Folder 304-306)
    - Llewelyn Davies, Michael, 1905–1921 (Box 10, Folder 307)
      One letter in mirror writing.
    - Llewelyn Davies, Nicholas, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 308)
      Series of letters written between September and December 1916 which contain part of a story titled "The Room with Two Beds."
    - Llewelyn Davies, Nicholas, 1916–1920; 1924–1935 (Box 10, Folder 309-314)
      First folder holds list of letters with précis for some.
    - Llewelyn Davies, Peter, 1903–1906 (Box 11, Folder 315)
    - Llewelyn Davies, Sylvia, 1892–1910 (Box 11, Folder 316-318)
    - Llewelyn Davies (unidentified), 1904 November 3 (Box 11, Folder 319)
      Illustrated letter to unidentified Llewelyn Davies boy.
    - Lloyd George, Margaret, 1923 April 17 (Box 11, Folder 320)
    - Locker, Arthur, 1891 February 15 (Box 11, Folder 321)
    - Loosemore, Mr. and Miss, 1907–1916 (Box 11, Folder 322)
    - Lucas, Audrey, 1921–1933 (Box 11, Folder 323)
      Letter of December 3, 1921, gift of Henry C. Taylor (Yale 1917), 1952.
    - Lucas, E. V. (Edward Verrall) and Elizabeth, 1917–1935 (Box 11, Folder 324)
      Containing a reference to letters submitted by Barrie to the Dumfries and Galloway Standard while a student at Dumfries Academy. Accompanied by a typed tribute to Charles Lamb with autograph revisions.
    - Lucas, Elizabeth, 1915–1937 (Box 11, Folder 325)
      Thirty-nine letters; the letter of August 10, 1935, gives details of Barrie's Mediterranean cruise.
      All letters except August 10, 1935, were the gift of Henry C. Taylor (Yale 1917), 1952.
    - "Lucy", 1913 August 2 (Box 11, Folder 326)
    - Lyell, Lady, undated (Box 11, Folder 327)
    - Lyell, Mrs., undated (Box 11, Folder 328)
    - McAllister, Donald, 1919; 1927 (Box 11, Folder 329)
    - MacArthur, Mr., 1902 April 16 (Box 11, Folder 330)
    - McArthur, Gertrude, 1911 December 11 (Box 11, Folder 331)
    - McCarthy, Lillah, 1908–1936 (Box 11, Folder 332)
      Forty-six letters bound in blue morocco by Sangorski & Sutcliffe. Bound with these letters is one autographed letter, signed, from Viola Meynell to Lady Keeble (Lillah McCarthy) concerning four of the letters published in Letters of J. M. Barrie, edited by Viola Meynell (New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1947).
    - McComb, Robert, 1898 November 5 (Box 11, Folder 333)
      Concerning Barrie's My Lady Nicotine. Published in Letters of J. M. Barrie, edited by Viola Meynell (New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1947).
    - MacDonald, Mr., 1924 (Box 11, Folder 334)
    - Mackail, Margaret, 1902 May 23 (Box 11, Folder 335)
    - Mackay, Eneas, 1903 March 7 (Box 11, Folder 336)
    - Mackenzie, Agnes Mure, 1915 August 27 (Box 11, Folder 337)
    - Macleay, John, 1896–1930 (Box 11, Folder 338)
      Includes one letter to Macleay from Arthur Quiller-Couch.
    - McLaren, Jack, 1927–1931 (Box 11, Folder 339)
    - Macleod, Donald, circa 1889; 1894 (Box 11, Folder 340)
      Earlier of the two letters outlines the plot of The Little Minister, first published in Good Words (January-December 1891), edited by Reverend Macleod.
    - Macmanus, J. E., undated (Box 12, Folder 341)
    - Main-Wright, Mr., 1926 December 9 (Box 12, Folder 342)
    - Mais, Stuart Peter Brodie (?), 1924–1930 (Box 12, Folder 343)
    - Malcolm, Mrs., undated (Box 12, Folder 344)
    - Mallaby, Angela Vanbrugh, 1902–1910 (Box 12, Folder 345)
    - "Malthus", 1922 March 23 (Box 12, Folder 346)
      Concerning the Stage Society.
    - Manson, James Alexander, 1896 September 6 (Box 12, Folder 347)
      Advising Manson about changes for the title page and spine of the first edition of Barrie's Sentimental Tommy (London, 1896). Removed from the copy of Sentimental Tommy presented to Manson by Barrie.
    - Marillier, H. C. (Henry Currie), and Mrs., 1905–1928 (Box 12, Folder 348)
    - "Marion", undated (Box 12, Folder 349)
    - Marriott, Charles, 1906–1912 (Box 12, Folder 350)
    - "Marsh", undated (Box 12, Folder 351)
    - Marshall, Ernest, 1917 February 14 (Box 12, Folder 352)
    - Martin, Miss, 1896 November 16 (Box 12, Folder 353)
    - Martin-Harvey, John, 1924–1936 (Box 12, Folder 354)
      The 1936 letters concern the production of The Boy David.
    - Martyn, May (Lady Playfair), 1905; 1906 (Box 12, Folder 355)
      Regarding Miss Martyn's job as an understudy in Peter Pan and her marriage to Nigel Playfair.
    - "Lady Mary", 1918 February 10 (Box 12, Folder 356)
    - Massie, Hughes, 1906 June 25 (Box 12, Folder 357)
    - Masson, Mrs., undated (Box 12, Folder 358)
    - Mathews, W. Lee, 1909 May 9 (Box 12, Folder 359)
    - Matthews, Brander?, 1918 September 26 (Box 12, Folder 360)
      Concerning Barrie's story "The Kaiser and his Dentist."
    - Maude, Cyril and Winifred Emery, 1902–1918 (Box 12, Folder 361)
      One letter to Cyril Maude removed from The Boy David (1938) (BEIN Ip B276 B65)
    - Maunsell, A. E. Lloyd (Arthur E. Lloyd), 1926 (Box 12, Folder 362)
    - Maxwell, Walter, 1906 May 10 (Box 12, Folder 363)
    - Meade, L. T., 1890 (Box 12, Folder 364)
    - Melrose, Mr., 1923 June 15 (Box 12, Folder 365)
    - Melville, Lewis [Lewis Saul Benjamin], 1906 October 9 (Box 12, Folder 366)
      Sending his subscription for the Titmarsh Club's first dinner which he was unable to attend.
    - Meredith, Marie E., 1892; 1898 (Box 12, Folder 367)
      Accepting an invitation to visit George Meredith at Box Hill.
    - Meredith, William Maxse, 1898–1936 (Box 12, Folder 368)
      One letter concerning a picture (possibly of George Meredith and Barrie) painted by Miss Draper and photographed by Hollyer, and a report that Barrie was going to adapt Evan Harrington for the stage.
    - Methuen, Algernon, 1894 July 8 (Box 12, Folder 369)
    - Meyer, Lady, 1913 June 6 (Box 12, Folder 370)
    - Miles, Alfred H. (Alfred Henry), 1892? Feb 8 (Box 12, Folder 371)
      Giving Miles permission to use 1500 words from Barrie's "The Courting of T'nowheads Bell."
    - Miller, Mr., 1908 April 15 (Box 12, Folder 372)
    - Mills, John F., 1895; 1896 (Box 12, Folder 373)
    - Milne, A. A. (Alan Alexander), 1925 (Box 12, Folder 374)
    - Milon, Mrs., undated (Box 12, Folder 375)
    - Minta, Mrs., 1931–1934 (Box 12, Folder 376)
    - Mitford, Mr., 1907 January 25 (Box 12, Folder 377)
    - Moore, George, 1930 (Box 12, Folder 378)
      Gift of Halsted B. VanderPoel, 1944.
    - Moore, T. Sturge (Thomas Sturge), undated (Box 12, Folder 379)
      Concerning an unsigned paper by Charles Dickens which appeared in Household Words.
    - Morgan, Mr., 1921 February 21 (Box 12, Folder 380)
      Concerning the death of George Llewelyn Davies.
    - Morley, George, 1905 March 4 (Box 12, Folder 381)
    - "Morrison", 1913 June 6 (Box 12, Folder 382)